Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. Correspondence with Henry Adams (MS Am 1751): Guide.
Correspondence with Henry Adams,
1861-1920.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1751
Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927.
2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
Correspondence of the American historian Brooks Adams to American novelist Henry Adams, as well as materials concerning the Adams' family.
*47M-120-135
Gift of Mrs. Robert Homans, 280 Beacon Street Boston, Massachusetts; received: 1947 September 15; 1948 November 30; 1948 January 5.
Brooks Adams was an American historian. Henry Adams was an American novelist, historian, and social critic.
Arranged chronologically
Also includes a lengthy critique by Henry Adams of an unpublished biography by Brooks Adams of John Quincy Adams, miscellaneous correspondence of Brooks Adams, letters from Charles Francis Adams to Brooks and Henry Adams.
- Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. 287 T.L.s. and A.L.s. and 2 fragments (signed variously) to Henry Adams; [v.p.] 1887-1916.
  Note: in this list, pieces all or mostly autograph are marked (A) those all or mostly typescript are marked (T).
  - Boston, 7 Mar 1887., (1); [3]p. with clipping. (A)
  - Boston, 8 Mar 1887., (2); 2l. (A)
  - Boston, 11 Mar 1887., (3); 2l. (A)
  - [Boston?] 22 Mar 1887., (4); 1l. (T)
  - Boston, 25 Mar 1887., (5); 1l. (A)
  - Vienna, 9 May 1887., (6); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 5 Apr 1888., (7); 1l. (A)
  - [Boston?] 12 Apr 1888., (8); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 18 Apr 1888., (9); 1l. (A)
  - [Boston] 27 Dec 1889., (10); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 26 Sep 1893., (11); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 8 Oct 1893., (12); folder (2l.) (A)
  - [Quincy?] 18 Oct 1893., (13); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 25 Nov 1893., (14); 3l. (A)
  - [Boston?] 4 Jan 1894., (15); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 6 May 1894., (16); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 9 May 1894., (17); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Venice, 30 Jun 1894., (18); [5]p. (A)
  - Boston, 14 Nov 1894., (19); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 19 Nov 1894., (20); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 22 Nov 1894., (21); 1l. (T)
  - Boston, 5 Dec 1894., (22); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 2 Feb 1895., (23); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 14 May 1895., (24); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 27 May 1895., (25); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 2 Jun 1895., (26); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 19 Jun 1895., (27); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 21 Jun 1895., (28); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 24 Jun 1895., (29); 4l. (T)
  - Quincy, 25 Jun 1895., (30); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 26 Jun [1895?], (31); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 30 Jun 1895., (32); 4l. (T)
  - Quincy, 24 Aug 1895., (33); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 21 Sep 1895., (34); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 13 Oct [18]95., (35); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Rome, 14 Nov 1895., (36); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Khandalla, 23 Dec 1895., (37); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Hyderabad, 23 Jan 1896., (38); 3 folders ([11]p.) (A)
  - Calcutta, 24 Feb 1896., (39); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Calcutta, 26 Feb 1896., (40); [5]p. (A)
  - Futtepur [i.e. Fatehpur] Sikri, 7 Mar 1896., (41); 3 folders ([12]p.) (A)
  - S.S. Guanean, 25 Mar 1896., (42); 3 folders ([12]p.) (A)
  - Cairo, 6 Apr 1896., (43); 3 folders ([12]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 22 Apr 1896., (44); [9]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 23 May 1896., (45); [4]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 13 Jun 1896., (46); [3]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 29 Jun 1896., (47); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 12 Jul 1896., (48); [3]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 19 Jul 1896., (49); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 26 Jul 1896., (50); [6]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 3 Aug 1896., (51); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 9 Aug 1896., (52); [3]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 17 Aug 1896., (53); [4]p. (T)
  - [Quincy?] 25 Aug 1896., (54); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 6 Sep 1896., (55); [4]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 12 Sep 1896., (56); [4]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 7 Oct 1896., (57); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 10 Oct 1896., (58); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 10 Oct 1896., (59); [3]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 15 Oct 1896., (60); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 18 Oct 1896., (61); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 Oct 1896., (62); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 21 Oct 1896., (63); [5]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 25 Oct 1896., (64); [5]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 28 Oct 1896., (65); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 31 Oct 1896., (66); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 22 Nov 1896., (67); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 8 Jan 1897., (68); [6]p. (A)
  - [Paris] 15 Jan 1897., (69); 3 folders ([10]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 19 Jan 1897., (70); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 27 Jan 1897., (71); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Paris] 29 Jan 1897., (72); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Paris] 4 Feb 1897., (73); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 16 Feb 1897., (74); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 26 Feb 1897., (75); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 5 Mar 1897., (76); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 8 Mar 1897., (77); [6]p. (A)
  - Paris, 14 Mar 1897., (78); 2 folders ([6]p.) (A)
  - [Washington] 21 Apr 1897., (79); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Washington] 29 Apr 1897., (80); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Washington, 10 May 1897., (81); cablegram (1l.)
  - [Washington] 10 May 1897., (82); [5]p. (A)
  - [Washington] 11 May 1897., (83); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Washington, 15 May 1897., (84); 2 folders ([6]p.)
  - Quincy, 27 May 1897., (85); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 1 Jun 1897., (86); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 8 Jul 1897., (87); 2l. (T)
  - Beverly Farms, 8 Aug 1897., (88); 3l. (T)
  - Beverly Farms, 6 Sep 1897., (89); [5]p. (T)
  - [Quincy?] 8 Oct 1897., (90); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 5 Nov 1897., (91); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Harrogate, 21 Nov 1897., (92); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [n.p., Dec 1897?], (93); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Paris, 6 Feb 1898., (94); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Paris, 11 Mar 1898., (95); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 14 Feb 1898., (96); [2]p. (T)
  - Paris, 20 Feb 1898., (97); [2]p. (T)
  - Paris, 27 Feb 1898., (98); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Paris, 26 Mar 1898., (99); [5]p. (A)
  - Washington, 29 Apr 1898., (100); [5]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 22 May 1898., (101); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 2 Jun 1898., (102); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 22 Jun 1898., (103); 1l. (T)
  - [London, ca. 15 Jul 1898], (104); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Paris, 24 Jul 1898., (105); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 17 Oct 1898., (106); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 20 Nov 1898., (107); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 29 Nov 1898., (108); 1l. (A)
  - Quincy, 18 Dec 1898., (109); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 25 Dec 1898., (110); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 28 Dec 1898., (111); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - St. Andrew, Jamaica, 15 Jan 1899., (112); [3]p. (A)
  - Washington, 10 Apr 1893 [i.e., 1899], (113); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 12 Jun 1899., (114); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 22 May 1899., (115); 3l.. (T)
  - Quincy, 5 Jul 1899., (116); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 6 Aug 1899., (117); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 11 Aug 1899., (118); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 17 Aug 1899., (119); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Berchtesgaden, 5 Sep 1899., (120); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 24 Sep 1899., (121); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 8 Oct 1899., (122); [5]p. (A)
  - Dresden, 14 Oct 1899., (123); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, [16 Oct 1899], (124); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 29 Oct 1899., (125); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 2 Nov 1899., (126); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 12 Nov 1899., (127); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 26 Nov 1899., (128); [2]p. (A)
  - Dresden, 2 Dec 1899., (129); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 17 Dec 1899., (130); [6]p. (A)
  - Dresden, 21 Dec 1899., (131); 2 folders ([6]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 25 Dec 1899., (132); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Dresden, 31 Dec 1899., (133); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Dresden, 25 Feb 1900., (134); 2 folders ([6]p.) (A)
  - London, 16 Mar 1900., (135); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 16 May 1900., (136); 5l. (T)
  - Quincy, 29 May 1900., (137); [5]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 22 Jun 1900., (138); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 19 Jul 1900., (139); 4l. (T)
  - Quincy, 11 Aug 1900., (140); 5l. (T)
  - Bedford, Pa., 26 Aug 1900., (141); [4]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 16 Sep 1900., (142); [4]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 11 Nov 1900., (143); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Quincy?] 13 Nov 1900., (144); 5l. (T)
  - Quincy, 29 Nov 1900., (145); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 2 Dec 1900., (146); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Athens, 28 Feb 1901., (147); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 Apr 1901., (148); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 30 Apr 1901., (149); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 5 May 1901., (150); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 8 May 1901., (151); 1l. (T)
  - [Quincy?] 13 May 1901., (152); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 6 Jun 1901., (153); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 27 Jun 1901., (154); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 5 Jul 1901., (155); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 15 Sep 1901., (156); 4l. (T)
  - Quincy, 13 Oct 1901., (157); 3l. (T)
  - Washington, 18 Nov 1901., (158); 2l. (T)
  - Charleston, S.C., 22 Jan 1902., (159); [2]p. (A)
  - Havana, 29 Jan 1902., (160); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Havana, 3 Feb 1902., (161); 1l. (A)
  - Mexico [City, Mexico] 18 Feb 1902., (162); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - San Antonio, Tex., 23 Feb 1902., (163); 3l. (A)
  - Asheville, N.C., 14 Mar 1902., (164); 3l. (A)
  - Boston, 2 Apr 1902., (165); [2]p. (A)
  - Boston, 6 Apr 1902., (166); [2]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 20 Apr 1902., (167); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 28 Apr 1902., (168); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 27 Jul 1902., (169); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 12 Sep 1902., (170); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 26 Sep 1902., (171); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 16 Oct 1902., (172); [4]p. (T)
  - Washington, 23 Nov 1902., (173); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Washington, 11 Dec 1902., (174); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Antibes, 3 Feb 1903., (175); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Hot Springs, Va., 1 May 1903., (176); [7]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 7 Jun 1903., (177); [8]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 20 Jun 1903., (178); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 5 Jul 1903., (179); 4l. (T)
  - Quincy, 20 Sep 1903., (180); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 1 Nov 1903., (181); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 8 May 1904., (182); 3l. (T)
  - Quincy, 13 May 1904., (183); 1l. (T)
  - Quincy, 23 May 1904., (184); [2]p. (T)
  - Quincy, 6 Oct 1904., (185); [6]p. (A)
  - Quincy, 12 May 1905., (186); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Woodstock, Vt., 2 Jul 1905., (187); [8]p. (A)
  - Boston, 7 Dec 1905., (188); 1l. (T)
  - Boston, 18 Dec 1905., (189); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 24 Dec 1905., (190); folder (2l.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 1 Jan 1906., (191); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 8 Jan 1906., (192); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 6 Apr 1906., (193); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 10 Apr 1906., (194); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 15 Apr 1906., (195); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 20 Apr 1906., (196); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 9 Oct 1906., (197); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 11 Nov 1906., (198); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 18 Dec 1906., (199); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 24 Feb 1907., (200); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 8 Mar 1907., (201); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 May 1907. 1l., with suggested codicil for will of Henry Adams, (202); (1l.) (T)
  - [Boston?] 1 Jan 1908., (203); [5]p. (A)
  - [Boston] 12 Mar 1908., (204); folder (2l.) (A)
  - [Boston] 18 Mar 1908., (205); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 15 Apr 1908., (206); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 25 Jun [1908], (207); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Paris, 28 Aug 1908., (208); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 16 Nov 1908., (209); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 21 Nov 1908., (210); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 28 Jan 1909., (211); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 8 Feb 1909., (212); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 10 Feb 1909., (213); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 15 Feb 1909., (214); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 19 Feb 1909., (215); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 22 Feb 1909., (216); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 6 Mar 1909., (217); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 8 Mar 1909., (218); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 21 Mar 1909., (219); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 23 Mar 1909., (220); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [London] 16 Jul 1909., (221); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 5 Aug 1909., (222); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 25 Jan 1910., (223); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 28 Jan 1910., (224); [6]p. (A)
  - Boston, 1 Mar 1910., (225); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 4 Mar 1910., (226); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 10 Mar 1910., (227); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 19 Mar 1910., (228); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 24 Mar 1910., (229); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 2 Apr 1910., (230); folder (1l.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 5 Apr 1910., (231); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 2 Aug 1910., (232); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 10 Aug 1910., (233); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 28 Sep 1910., (234); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 22 Oct 1910., (235); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 12 Nov 1910., (236); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 6 Dec 1910., (237); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 23 Jan 1911., (238); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston?] 17 Feb 1911., (239); folder ([2]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 4 Apr 1911., (240); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 9 Apr 1911., (241); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 7 May 1911., (242); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Paris, 28 Jul 1911., (243); 1l. (A)
  - Kissingen, 20 Aug 1911., (244); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Kissingen, 25 Aug 1911., (245); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 27 Feb 1912., (246); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 2 Mar 1912., (247); [5]p. (A)
  - Boston, 7 Mar 1912., (248); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 10 Mar 1912., (249); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 18 Mar 1912., (250); 2l. (T)
  - Boston, 22 Mar 1912., (251); [6]p. (A)
  - Boston, 26 Mar 1912., (252); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 31 Mar 1912., (253); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 7 Apr 1912., (254); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 24 Jun 1912., (255); 1l. (T)
  - Kissingen, 28 Jul 1912., (256); 2 folders ([6]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 11 Sep 1912., (257); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 15 Sep 1912., (258); 3l. (T)
  - Boston, 17 Sep 1912., (259); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 Sep 1912., (260); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 25 Sep 1912., (261); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 27 Sep 1912., (262); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 14 Oct 1912., (263); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 22 Oct 1912., (264); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 5 Nov 1912., (265); [5]p. (A)
  - Boston, 15 Nov 1912., (266); 3l. (A)
  - Boston, 28 Nov 1912., (267); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 3 Dec 1912., (268); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 8 Dec 1912., (269); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 18 Dec 1912., (270); 2 folders ([7]p.) (A)
  - [Boston] 7 Jan 1913., (271); [2]p. (A)
  - Boston, 5 Feb 1913., (272); 2l. (T)
  - Quincy, 1 Oct 1913., (273); 2 folders ([8]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 10 Nov 1913., (274); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 13 Dec 1913., (275); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Boston, 21 Dec 1913., (276); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, [25 Dec] 1913., (277); folder ([4]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 7 Jan 1915., (278); 3l. (T)
  - Boston, 20 Mar 1915., (279); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Boston, 25 Mar 1915., (280); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 May 1915., (281); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 24 May 1915., (282); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 27 May 1915., (283); folder (1l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 24 Jun 1915., (284); 2 folders ([5]p.) (A)
  - Quincy, 19 Aug 1915., (285); folder (2l.) (A)
  - Quincy, 26 Oct 1915., (286); folder ([3]p.) (A)
  - Boston, 7 Mar 1916., (287); 1l. (T)
  - Fragment; [n.p., n.d.], (288); folder ([2] p.) (A)
  - Fragment; [n.p., n.d.], (289); 1l. (T)
- Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [] Brett; Bath [Me.] 17 Nov 1896., (290); folder ([3]p.)
  *47M-121
- Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to Mrs. [] Baker; Quincy 28 Oct 1913., (291); folder ([2]p.)
  *47M-122
- Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to Miss [] Tone; Boston, 5 Nov 1916., (292); folder ([3]p.)
  *47M-123
- Abbott, Samuel A B A.L.s.(Saml. A. B. Abbott) to Henry Adams; Ponte Milvio [Italy] 29 Nov 1912., (293); [2]p.
  *47M-124
- Koopman, Harry Lyman, 1860- A.L.s.(H. L. Koopman) to Henry Adams; Providence, R.I., 22 Jan 1912., (294); [2]p.; *47M-125
- Norcross, Grenville H. A.L.s.(Grenville H. Norcross) to Brooks Adams; [Boston] 31 Mar 1910., (295); 1l.
  *47M-126
- Bebel, August, 1840-1913. A.L.s.(A. Bebel) to []; Berlin, 2 Nov 1899., (296); 1l.
  *47M-127
- Towne, Charles Arnette, 1858- A.L.s.(Chas. A. Towne) to [Brooks] Adams; Delano, Minn., 16 Oct 1896., (297); 2l.
  *47M-128
  Was enclosed with letter of Brooks to Henry Adams, 19 Oct 1896. (q.v.)
- Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915. T.L.s.(Charles F. Adams) to Henry Adams; 12 Dec 1905., (298); 2l.
  *47M-129
- Adams, Charles Francis, 1866- T.L.s.(C. F. Adams 2nd) to Henry Adams; 7 Jul 1896., (299); 2l.
  *47M-130
- Adams, Charles Francis, 1866- T.L.s.(C. F. Adams 2nd.) to Brooks Adams; 13 Nov 1901., (300); 2l.
  *47M-131
- Adams, Mary (Ogden) A.L.s.(Mary Ogden Adams) to Henry [Adams]; S. Lincoln, Mass., 8 Oct 1915., (301); folder ([3]p.)
  *47M-132
- Adams, Evelyn (Davis) 4 A.LL.s.(variously) to Henry [Adams]; [v.p., v.d.], (302-305)
  *47M-133
- Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. 3 A.LL.s.(variously) to Brooks [Adams]; [v.p. v.d.]
  *47M-134
  - Washington, 18 Feb 1909., (306); 13l.
    Enclosing his critique (82l.) on an unpublished biography by Brooks Adams of John Quincy Adams.
  - [Washington?] 13 Mar 1909., (307); folder ([4]p.)
  - [N.p.] 23 Aug 1911., (308); 6 folders (12l.)
- Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924. T.L.s.(H. C. Lodge) to Brooks Adams; [Washington] 22 Jan 1920., (309); folder (1l.)
  *47M-135
- Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. 3 L.s. to Abigail [(Adams) Homans]; [v.p.],; 8 Apr. - 25 May 1898., (310-312); 1 folder
  The letters deal with the opening phases of the Spanish-American war.
  Received: 30 Nov. 1948.
- Adams, John Quincy, 1833-1894. 10 A.L.s. to Charles Francis Adams; [v.p.]; 7 Jan. - 30 Dec. 1861., (312-322); 1 folder
  Received: 15 Sept. 1947.
- Adams, John Quincy, 1833-1894. 6 A.L.s. to Charles Francis Adams; [v.p.]; 7 Jan. - 30 Dec. 1861., (323-328); 1 folder
- Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. 140 A.L.s. and 2 fragments to Brooks Adams; [v.p.]; 5 Jun 1895 - 10 Feb. 1914., (329-470); 23 folders
- Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s. to Mrs. Brooks Adams; [Paris, 29 May 1911]., (471); 1 folder, with envelope.